# **Dennis Kamau**



dmkamau475@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/denmau



0759360020



https://denmau.me

### **Summary**

TensorFlow certified Machine Learning Engineer with frontend and backend skills. Today, I am focusing on delivering APIs that scale. Familiar with the Software Development patterns, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Agile Methodologies.

My skills span from software design, building mobile applications with Flutter and Java, Web frontends with Vue.js, and the backend with Django or PHP. Experienced with containers (Docker), API integration, and setting up deployment pipelines on Heroku, Amazon Web Services (AWS), and Google Cloud Platform (GCP). For Databases, I am comfortable with MySQL, PostgreSQL, and Firebase. I am a huge fan of Jetbrains IDEs. If you catch me outside of work, I'm an adventurous traveler and an avid lover of basketball!

### **Experience**

### Junior Web Developer (PHP and Flutter)

Startappz Limited

Jul 2021 - Present (3 months +)

- Developing bespoke Web applications with PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, and HTML/CSS.
- Developing Mobile applications with Flutter, often while collaborating with a UI/UX Designer.
- Developed beautiful UI for internal tools and automating backend tasks.
- API integrations and Database management.
- Helping with System Architecture for software solutions.

### **Solution** Junior Machine Learning Engineer

#### Omdena

May 2021 - Jul 2021 (3 months)

- Reduced business expenses by implementing computer vision with OpenCV.
- Built and optimized Machine Learning models with TensorFlow.
- Conceptualized APIs to serve ML models to edge devices.
- · Collaborated with a remote team on Slack, with weekly meetings with the business owner.

### zuri. Backend Developer Intern

Zuri Team, Inc.

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 (4 months)

- Work on Full-Stack web projects with Python Django.
- Collaborate with other interns on projects over slack as a Backend Developer.
- Worked on a site that links drivers to a mechanic from any part of Nigeria!
- Used tools such as Python, Django, and SQL.

## Frontend Developer, BuildForSDG Challenge 2020

#### Andela

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 (5 months)

- · Collaborated in an agile remote team to innovate on real-world, locally and relevant solutions focused on the Sustainable Development Goals(SDGs).
- worked on a team project to connect farmers to consumers.
- Prepared visual presentations for team meetings.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and jQuery.

#### **Education**



#### South Eastern Kenya University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2019 - May 2021



#### eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Bootcamp, Android App Development

2021 - 2021

- · Android Java
- Firebase
- SQLite
- Location & google Maps
- APIs & Networking



#### eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Full Stack Web Development bootcamp, Computer Software and Media Applications 2021 - 2021

Gave me a very firm foundation in

- PHP
- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS



#### Apps:Lab

21C Skills Training, Software Engineering

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Strong Computer Science foundation and Data Structures & Algorithms.
- · Learned the importance of Testing and how to go about it.
- Setting up deployment pipelines for web and mobile applications.
- Got in touch with a Mentor.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



#### Digital Assurance Virtual Case Experience - PwC

RmZ3iX93HE44pFDQP



### **DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization** - Coursera

QP3343SDDDGG

- Sequences, Time Series and Prediction Coursera 5GNZSFWDBGPP
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning Coursera

  E8SJVW7MX7EM
- Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow Coursera
  PX9MDXB4XPM8
- Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow Coursera
  9NR2HSGNE5PY
- TensorFlow Developer Certificate TensorFlow Certificate Program 38536516

#### **Skills**

Android • python • PHP • Machine Learning • Web Applications • Django • TensorFlow • SQL • Microsoft Power BI • java